- 嗨   - 嗨
- Hi.     - Hi.
你好 我是菲比布非 我底下有宝宝要出来
Hi. Yeah, hi. I'm, um, Phoebe Buffay and I have babies coming out.
好 你开始阵痛了吗？
Okay. Have you started having contractions?
还没听说会很痛 真的吗？
Not yet. Um, I heard they really hurt. Do they?
- 这么嘛…   - 天哪
- Well...     - Oh, my God.
哪一位是父亲？
Which of you is the father?
他们都不是 我弟才是
None of them are. The father is my brother.
好吧
Okay.
我一定会很怀念你那样吓别人
I'll miss watching you freak people out like that.
菲比
Pheebs...
快 这是要给宝宝看的
This is for the babies to look at someday.
在生产前你有话要说吗？
Do you want to say anything before it starts?
好吧
Okay. Um...
孩子们 我是菲比姑姑
Hi, kids! Um, it's me, Aunt Phoebe.
真想赶快见到你们 请不要弄痛我
Can't wait to see you. Please don't hurt me.
你们怎么那么慢？
What took you so long?
两辆车是一起出发的
Your cab left when ours did.
我们回去拿我的外套
We went back because I forgot my jacket.
你没穿外套啊
You're not wearing one.
真是的 我又忘了
Oh, man! I did it again!
得有人通知法兰克和爱丽丝
Someone has to call Frank and Alice.
我妈也想… 乔伊 你干什么？
My mom might... What are you doing?
我得拍生产前的镜头
I've got to get the before shot.
菲比 我们问过护士了 你的医生之所以迟到…
We spoke to the nurse. The reason your doctor is late...
是因为她不来了
...is because, uh, she's not coming.
- 什么？ - 她在浴室跌倒撞到头了
- What?     - She hit her head in the shower.
天哪 那个蠢女人
Oh, my God. She's so stupid!
菲比 不会有事的
Pheebs, it's going to be okay.
你说得轻松 你的阴道又没有宝宝要出来
I don't see three kids coming out of your vagina.
听着 护士说这个医生很好
Listen. The nurse said the doctor is wonderful.
对 他是妇产科主任
He's head of the department.
好吧 老天爷救救我
All right. Ooh. Oh, dear God, save me.
第一次阵痛来了
I'm having my first contraction.
- 还好嘛   - 好
- Oh, it's not bad.     - Okay.
生命的奇迹开始了…
And so the miracle of birth begins. And I...
你没事吧？
You okay?
有个地方好痛
Something hurts.
是感同身受 如此甜蜜啊
Ooh, it's sympathy pains. Oh, that's so sweet.
我不知道我有那么在意
I didn't know I cared that much.
- 你好   - 你好
- Hello.      - Hi.
我是哈洛医生 我负责替你接生
I'm Dr. Harad. I'll be delivering your babies.
有我在你放心 我是老手了
You'll be in good hands. I've been doing this a long time.
我马上回来帮你做检查
I'll be back to do your internal.
你先放轻松 目前一切都很好
Just relax, everything looks great.
还有 我爱方奇
And also, I love Fonzie.
他刚才说他爱方奇吗？
Did he just say he loves Fonzie?
听起来是
That's what it sounded like.
好
All right.
嘿
Hey!
我来晚了吗？还没有人出来吧？
Am I late? Nobody came out yet, right?
没有 还没开始呢 爱丽丝呢？
No, we haven't started yet. Where's Alice?
在德拉威 不过她正在赶来 目前先由我充当教练
Uh, Delaware. Until she gets here, I'll be your coach.
放心 她有教我拉马兹什么的
Don't worry. She told me about the LaMazda stuff.
就是在月底前生产
If you get the babies out by month's end...
就能获得2%的补助
...you get two percent financing.
对
Yeah.
摩妮卡 你一定会很以我为荣
Monica, you're going to be very proud of me.
我帮我们约到两个俏护士
I just got us dates with two unbelievably cute nurses.
喔 我
Oh, my.
是男看护
They're male nurses.
在我想像中不是
Heh, heh. Not in my head.
他们约我们周六晚上出去 如何？
They want to take us out Saturday night. What do you say?
额
Um...
- 我看算了   - 什么？
- I don't think so.      - What?
什么叫算了？
What are you talking about?
是你劝我忘记罗斯向前看的
You've been telling me to get over Ross and move on.
我向前看了 你得陪我
I'm moving on and so are you.
你说 你为什么不去
Why don't you want to go?
额
Um...
不如你说一个理由
Why don't you give me a good reason...
我再告诉你是对是错
...and I'll tell you if it's true.
- 什么？ - 没那么简单吧？
- What?      - Harder than it sounds, isn't it?
总之你也要去 我还答应他们下班…
You're coming. And when they get off...
一起去吃果冻
...we'll go get some Jello with them.
没错 人永远吃得下果冻
Yep. There's always room for Jello.
你为什么能说得那么色？
How do you make that dirty?
简单 我什么都能说得很色
It's easy. I can do it with anything.
奶奶的鸡肉沙拉…
Grandma's chicken salad...
罗斯
Ross!
拍这里
Get a shot of this.
这是你们出生当天的头条
Hey, babies, these are the headlines when you were born.
女宝宝把头转开 男宝宝…
Now girl baby, turn away. And boy babies...
看看
...check it out.
这就是你出生当月的裸女
This is what naked women looked like when you were born.
尽情欣赏吧
Now let's dive into the good stuff.
好 阵痛又来了
Okay, I'm having another one.
这次也不太痛… 错 很痛
This one doesn't hurt eith... Ooh, yes, it does! Ow.
噢 噢 噢
Ow, ow, ow!
啊
Ooh.
我有点希望已经生了
Ooh, I was kind of hoping that was it.
摩妮卡和瑞秋呢？
Where are Monica and Rachel, anyway?
可能跟约她们的护士在一起
A couple of nurses asked them out. Maybe they're with them.
是吗？男看护？
Really? Male nurses?
对 我也很失望
Yeah, I was bummed too.
她们要去约会？
So they're going on dates?
- 什么时候？ - 星期六吧…
- When?     - I think Saturday.
- 他怎么了？ - 他感同身受
- What's with him?      - Um, sympathy pains.
我本来很感动 现在我觉得他只是想抢风头
It was sweet at first, but now I think he's trying to steal my thunder.
好吧
Okay.
来看看你的情况
Let's see what we got here.
你知道吗？方奇跟三胞胎约过会
Oh, you know, Fonzie dated triplets.
你一直提到的这位方奇
This Fonzie person you keep referring to...
他是另一位医生吗？
...is that another doctor?
不是
Oh, no, no.
方奇是亚瑟方塞瑞利的昵称
Fonzie is the nickname of Arthur Fonzerelli.
也叫方子
The Fonz.
好
All right.
很快了
Soon.
其实不会很怪吧？
It's not that weird, is it?
怪得不得了
It's very weird.
我才不要听某人告诉我 我扩张了"一滴滴"
I don't want some guy down there telling me I'm "dilated-a-mundo."
老实说 他不是在模仿方奇…
He doesn't seem to be impersonating Fonzie...
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
干嘛替他辩解？去帮我另外找一个没有发疯的医生
Why are you defending him? Just get me another doctor...
不是方奇的医生
...who isn't crazy and doesn't Fonzie!
- 其实他不是…   - 啊 啊
- Again, it's not...      - Aah! Aah!
嘿 你在这里
Hey, there you are.
有件事应该让你知道
Um, there's something you should know.
是你要跟护士约会的事吗？我听乔伊说了
Is this about you dating the nurse? Joey told me.
我一点也不在意 你和我又没什么
I am so fine. You and I, we're just, nothing.
我们只是玩玩
Just goofing around.
其实我是想告诉你我打算推掉
Um, I was about to tell you I was getting out of it.
既然我们只是玩玩 那我就跟他出去好了
But, um, if we're just "goofing around," maybe I will go out with him.
好 那我也要
Fine. Maybe I will too.
喂 你们看我在礼品店发现了什么…
Hey! Look what I found in the gift shop...
起来 快起来
Oh. Get up! Get up! Get up!
菲比
Okay, Pheebs?
这是欧伯曼医生
This is Dr. Oberman.
他对方奇或《欢乐时光》里的所有人物…
He has no strong feelings about Fonzie...
都没什么感觉
...or any of the Happy Days gang.
你要升几年级？
You're going into what grade?
我刚升住院医师 常有人那样问我 我提前…
I'm actually a first-year resident. I graduated early.
我也是
Uh-huh. Me too.
罗斯 或许我应该强调 我是要已成年的医师
Ross, I should have specified I'd need a grown-up doctor.
我绝对有能力…
Really, I'm fully qualified...
闭嘴
Shh, Doogie. Shh.
到底有没有人了解我快生了？
Doesn't anybody understand that I'm going to be having babies soon? Huh?
你走 走啊 小毛头
Go, little boy! Go!
你把他弄哭了
Oh, cool. You made him cry!
崔比亚尼先生 你有肾结石
Mr. Tribbiani, I'm afraid you've got kidney stones.
有别的可能吗？
Uh, well, what else could it be?
就是肾结石
It's kidney stones.
或是…
Or...
肾结石
Kidney stones.
差不多了
You're getting there.
这些宝宝很幸运
These babies are very, very lucky.
是吗 为什么？
They are? Why?
他们的生日日期是方子的一半
They'll be born on the Fonz's half-birthday.
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
我澄清一下
Just to clarify.
我不是方奇
I'm not Fonzie.
耶额
Yeah.
说真的 你能替你弟生孩子真的很棒
It's a terrific thing that you're having these babies for Frank and Alice.
- 的确   - 对啊
- I know, it is.      - Yeah.
- 我可以告诉你个秘密吗？ - 你说
- Can I tell you a secret?     - Yeah.
我要自己留一个
I want to keep one.
天哪 我要上新闻
Oh, I'm going to be on the news.
菲比 别开玩笑了
You've gotta be kidding.
你明知道你不能这么做
You know you can't keep one of these babies.
为什么？搞不好可以 你怎么知道
Maybe I can. You don't know.
我当然知道 法兰克他们一定三个都要
I do. Frank and Alice will want to keep all their children.
不一定 你知道吗？
Maybe not. You know?
三个宝宝很多
Three babies are a handful.
也许他们正在找机会送走一个
Maybe they'll want to unload one.
我不想因为没开口而失去机会
I hate to miss an opportunity because I didn't ask.
菲比 这件事太扯了
Phoebe, no. This is insane.
你就问问看嘛
Just ask him.
什么？我？
What? Me?
我不能自己问
I can't ask him!
你知道那样多不成体统吗？
Do you know how inappropriate that would be?
总之你去找法兰克谈
All I'm saying is, just talk to Frank.
探探他的口风
Just feel him out.
不行 我怎么能叫法兰克 送你一个孩子
No. I will not ask Frank to give you one of his kids.
你说得对
You're right.
就说是你要的
Tell him it's for you.
好一点了吗？
Feeling better, sweetie?
一点点吧
Maybe a little.
真希望你没看到我吐
Wish you hadn't seen me throw up.
我也希望
Me too.
我刚刚听说 怎么回事？
Hey. I just heard. What's up?
肾结石
Kidney stones.
通常我们会用冲击波震碎结石
Ordinarily, we try to break the stones up with shock waves.
但你的结石已经太靠近膀胱
But they're too close to the bladder.
不是等你排尿排出来 震是从尿道往上…
Either we wait for you to pass them or else go up the urethra...
哇哦哦
Whoa!
不行 不能往上
No, no, no. Nothing is going "up," okay?
绝对不考虑往上 尿道是什么？
"Up" is not an option. What's a urethra?
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?
你问他了吗？
Did you ask him?
我还没有机会跟他独处
No, I haven't had a chance yet.
我的时间有限
I'm kind of on a clock here.
方奇
Oh, Fonzie.
我一直都很喜欢魔克
You know who I always liked? Mork.
收回 收回
Undo it. Undo it. Undo it.
方奇见过魔克
Fonzie met Mork.
魔克把方奇结冻
Mork froze Fonzie.
对 但…
Yeah...
对
Yes...
但是方奇本来就很酷
...but Fonzie was already cool.
所以他不会有事 对吧？
So he wasn't hurt. Right?
也对
Yeah, that's right.
你好吗？
How you doing?
很好 医生说随时都会生
Okay. Doctor says any minute now.
爱丽丝马上就会到
You know, Alice is going to be here so soon.
你能不能帮个忙 先留住？
You couldn't just do me a favor and, like, hold them in?
抱歉 我正在处理你请我帮的最后一个忙
Sorry, I'm in the middle of the last favor you asked me to do.
嘿 瑞秋 嗨
Hey, Rachel. Hi!
摩妮卡 他是丹 我们星期六的男伴之一
This is Dan, one of the guys we're going out with on Saturday.
丹 这是摩妮卡
Dan, Monica.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
你好 丹
Hello, Dan.
我很期待星期六的约会 非常期持
I'm really looking forward to Saturday night. Really! Really!
丹
So Dan...
你是护士不是医生？
Nurse, not a doctor, huh?
有点娘娘腔对吧？
Kind of girlie, isn't it?
- 钱德   - 没关系
- Chandler.     - That's okay.
这只是为了挣钱 好上完医学院
I'm doing this to get through medical school.
噢
Oh.
而且海湾战争时 感觉没那么娘娘腔
And it didn't feel "girlie" during the Gulf War.
那当然
Sure.
感谢你保家卫国
Thanks for doing that for us, by the way.
何必等到星期六 你明天有空吗？
Why wait till Saturday? Are you free tomorrow?
行啊 我找人代班
Sure. I'll get somebody to cover me.
太好了
Aw, great.
我们星期六去约个会如何？
Hey, you and me, Saturday night?
- 不要   - 很好
- No.     - All right, very good!
这一回很痛
This is a big one.
把它弄出来
Unh! Get these things out of me!
深呼吸 深呼吸可以止痛
Breathe! Breathe through the pain.
我想吃止痛药 我想吃止痛药
I want the drugs, Ross!
我也是 我也是
I do too! I do too!
我爱你 再见
Yeah, I love you. Okay, bye.
- 嗨   - 嗨
- Hi.     - Hi.
爱丽丝的妈说她出发5小时了
That was Alice's mom. Alice left five hours ago.
她早就该到了
She should be here.
放心 她会赶上的
She'll make it on time.
- 好   - 对啊
- Yeah.     - Yeah.
法兰克…
So Frank...
三个宝宝耶 还真多 对吧？
Three babies. Whoo, that just seems like a lot, huh?
我不觉得
Not to me.
很好
Fair enough.
扩张10公分 该生了
You're at 10 centimeters. Time to start having babies.
请父亲留下来就好
I want only the father here.
- 爱你哦   - 加油
- We love you.      - Good luck.
- 丹 再见   - 再见 摩妮卡
- Bye, Dan!     - Uh, bye, Monica.
我要产钳 消毒毛巾和31频道
I need a clamp, a sterile towel and Channel 31.
那是什么？
What is that?
天哪
Oh, my God!
不会 这一集很棒 方奇玩曼波鼓
Oh, no, no! It's a good one. Fonzie plays the bongos.
准备好了吗？该用力了
Ready? Time to try pushing.
准备好了吗？该撒尿了
Ready? Time to try peeing.
等等 是差不多该撒尿了
Wait, wait, wait, wait! It's almost time to try peeing.
用力 很好 专心用力
Push. Concentrate on pushing.
有了 我看到头了
I see the head.
万岁 他有头
Yes, it is a head!
继续用力 加油
Keep pushing. Come on.
居然有人从你肚子里跑出来
I can't believe somebody's coming out!
有人从你肚子里跑出来
There's somebody coming out of you!
是我儿子
It's my son!
好的
All right.
这是你的第一个宝宝
Here's your first baby.
万岁
Yes!
万岁 小男生出来了
Yes! We got a baby boy!
法兰克二世 二世
Frank Junior, Junior!
他长得怎样？
How does he look?
粗俗死了
So gross!
好 可以再用力了吗？
Okay. You ready to push again?
我已经生一个了 不要烦我
I already had a baby. Leave me alone.
加油 你一定行
Come on, you can do it. You can do it.
万岁
Yeah!
小莱丝莉出来了
Little Leslie's here! We got another one!
天哪 我居然有两个孩子了
Oh, my God! I can't believe I have two children.
真吓人
How scary is that?
小钱德 快啊 该出来了 小钱德
Come on, little Chandler, it's time to be born.
他出来了 他出来了
He's coming! Yes, he's coming!
他的小象呢？
Hey, where's his thing?
钱德是女生
Chandler's a girl!
天哪 幼稚园回忆重现
Oh, God. Kindergarten flashback.
一定是照超音波看错了 医生以为是个男生
They read the sonogram wrong, because they thought it was a boy.
但钱德是女生 钱德是女生
But Chandler's a girl! Chandler's a girl!
很好 继续叫
Okay, keep saying it.
- 来晚了吗？ - 没有 一切都很好
- Am I too late?     - No, no. Everything's okay.
每个宝宝都好手好脚的
There's 30 fingers and 30 toes.
我们的孩子生了？
We have our babies?
对
Yeah.
我们有孩子了
We have our babies.
天哪
Oh, my God.
你办到了
You did it, man.
你要看看它们吗？
Would you like to see them?
好小喔
They're so small.
- 我明天跟你联络   - 好
- I'll call you tomorrow.     - Great.
你真的要跟那个男护士约会？
Are you really going to date that nurse man?
你和我只是"玩玩"
You and I are just "goofing around."
我当然也可以跟他"玩玩"
I thought, why not "goof around" with him?
我不知道你有没有查过字典
I don't know if you've looked up "goofing around" in the dictionary.
我有
Well, I have...
"玩玩"的定义是…
...and the technical definition is:
"两个好朋友 非常在乎对方
"Two friends who care a lot about each other...
在床上很性福
...and have amazing sex...
而且想多跟对方相处"
...and just want to spend more time together."
如果你用的是这个版本那真是让你气死我了
But if you have this new dictionary that gets you mad at me...
那我们应该买我的版本给你
...then we have to get you my original dictionary.
我实在很糟糕
I am so bad at this.
- 比你想像的要好   - 真的？
- You're better than you think you are.     - Really?
好 那…
Okay. So if...
- 要见好就收   - 我也觉得够了
- Know when to stop.     - I sensed that I should stop.
- 我们没事了？ - 没事了
- So we're okay?      - Yeah.
我去告诉丹我不跟他约会
I'm gonna go tell Dan that it's not going to happen.
- 不要跳舞   - 好
- Don't do the dance.     - Right.
我觉得我最喜欢你
You're my favorite.
- 你抱的是哪个？ - 无所谓
- Which one do you have?     - I don't care.
嗨
Hi.
嘿
Hey.
法兰克和爱丽丝说 他们还要打电话
Frank and Alice want me to tell you they're making phone calls.
你有没有问他们…
Did you talk to them about, you know...
这个嘛…
Yeah, um...
没有
No, honey.
噢 好吧
Oh, okay.
反正也不太可能
It was a long shot.
让我跟宝宝独处一下好吗？
You guys? Can I just have a second alone with the babies?
好
Yeah.
你们都在了
So here you are.
我对着培养皿跟你们说话 彷佛是昨天的事
Seems like yesterday I was talking to you in that petri dish.
大家都说生产最难熬
Everyone said labor was the hardest thing.
其实跟你们分开才是
But they were wrong. This is.
这段日子真的很开心
Well, I had the most fun with you guys.
真想带你们回家每天看着你们
I wish I could take you home and see you every day.
我就当你们最喜欢的姑姑吧
I'll settle for being your favorite aunt.
爱丽丝的妹妹家有游泳池 但你们在我肚子里游过
I know Alice's sister has a pool, but you lived in me.
那就这样了
Okay, so we're cool.
我们会处得很好
We're going to be great.
小击掌
Little high-fives.
啊 啊 啊
Aah, aah, aah.
既然你都哭了
Well, if you're going to cry...
菲比 我们好以你为荣 你真了不起
Phoebe, we are so proud of you. You're amazing!
我知道
I know.
真的有那么痛吗？
Does it hurt as bad as they say?
你绝对受不了
You won't be able to take it.
既然小钱德是个女生 他们打算叫她什么？
Now that little Chandler is a girl, what'll they name her?
就叫她钱德
They'll call her Chandler.
这个名字有点男性化吧？
Kind of a masculine name, don't you think?
你都能用了
It works on you.